

25B Yeats Village, Ballinode, Sligo

085 2155306

davidwbrennan@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/Daithy in

https://github.com/s00172994

www.daithy.com





PERSONAL PROFILE

A diligent, enthusiastic and artistic student currently studying BSc. in Computing in Games Development at Institute of Technology, Sligo. I work in game engines such as Unity, MonoGame and GameMaker: Studio, specializing in object-oriented languages. I develop in C# and TypeScript with a flair for effective communication, perfecting versatile skills and leading successful projects.



SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- Proficient in .NET, C# and TypeScript with 3 years' experience each.
- Adept at data structures, algorithms, problem-solving, end-to-end
- Learning C++ (<1 year), JavaScript (1 year) and Java (<1 year).

Additional Skills:

- LINQ, WPF, ASP.NET, MVC, SQL, XAML and Angular.
- A* Algorithm, Entity Framework, Optimization techniques.
- Experience in Xbox One, Mobile, Web, VR and cloud-based platforms.
- Agile Methodologies, Scrum, Extreme Programming.
- **3D Graphics**, **vertex** and **particle shader** knowledge.
- High level of expertise in digital art, texturing and modeling.
- Skilled in teamwork, leadership and creative thinking.
- Quick to pick up new languages or frameworks.

Source Control Tools:

Git

Tool Proficiency:

- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- ReSharper
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Audacity
- FL Studio
- Paint.NET
- Maya 3D
- Source SDK



EDUCATION

BSc. in Computing in Games Development (Level 7) | IT Sligo, Sligo

2016 - PRESENT

2nd Year GPA: 84.16%

1st Year GPA: 81.16%

As a Student Mentor in 2018, I take pride in helping students fit in at IT Sligo. I discussed class group feedback with my lecturers as a Class Representative in 2016-2017. In my free time, I like to actively participate in several societies including Games Society and IT Sligo's Badminton team, competing in Badminton Intervarsities 2017 and ISBT Limerick 2017.

I received 2 awards by competing in Games Fleadh 2018, I had a lot of fun learning from other competing teams and advice obtained from judging experts. I plan to enter again with a team of 4 in 2019.

Leaving Certificate | St. Mary's C.B.S. (Coláiste Mhuire), Mullingar

2010 - 2015

• Final Score: 330 Points

Nominated Student of the Year 2015 by year head.



AWARDS

Game Studio Ireland Challenge - College Runner-Up

Game Studio Ireland Challenge - Best Windows Platform (UWP) Game |

Games Fleadh 2018 – Digital Programming Festival

MARCH 2018

Both awards received from Prof. Vincent Cunnane (*President LIT*) and Stephen Howell (*Microsoft Ireland*).

Games Development - Year 1 Games Competition Runner Up | IT Sligo

APRIL 2017

Award received from Games Development lecturers Neil Gannon and Paul Powell.



PROJECTS

Project Dissonance | C#

MAY 2018 - PRESENT

Project Dissonance is my final 3rd-year project being developed in Unity 3D. My goal is to execute complex game mechanics, make use of 3D camera movements, animation, particle systems, weather-based event system and 3D physics. I aim to be a team player with the role of project lead and gameplay programmer.

Steel Wrath | C#

NOVEMBER 2017 - MARCH 2018

Steel Wrath is a **2D top-down**, tank shoot 'em up that features **smooth tank controls**, tank crew **power-up mechanics**, **procedurally generated** tank spawns and tank types. I implemented an **A* path-finding algorithm** in combination with my own **custom Al behaviors** for enemy **Al tanks**. I undertook all the roles necessary for this project and achieved to meet every objective on my own.

Cry of Fear — Halloween Collaboration | C++

NOVEMBER 2012 - NOVEMBER 2012

At 15 years of age, using Valve Software's GoldSrc engine I entered my custom campaign entry. I worked with community mappers over Skype calls and mapped in Hammer which involved map planning with drawn map sketches, scripting, modeling, map brushes and texture mapping. I gained tons of player feedback from this custom-campaign entry, including a reaction from YouTube personality, 'Markiplier'.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Customer Assistant | Tesco

AUGUST 2015 - OCTOBER 2016

I improved my **interpersonal skills** in a working **team environment**, taking up a year of work at Tesco, gaining further insight into the **world of business**. I solved **complicated customer queries** and was **trained** in many areas of the workplace being **front-end**, **floors** and **self-service maintenance**.

General Assistant | Mullingar Arts Centre

2014 - 2016

I have taken numerous jobs and performed shows in the Arts Centre over the years. The performing arts has enlightened me to **gain confidence** and grow not just as an artist but as an individual.

- Bartender work
- Reception work
- Ushering

- Front desk cashier work
- Stage lighting
- Stage handwork

- Acting & Performing
- Singing
- Presentation Skills



REFERENCES

Neil Gannon | Games Development Lecturer, IT Sligo **♦**: 087 9231797 Paul Powell | Games Programming Lecturer, IT Sligo €: 071 9305709